Guide to the Records of Governor James S. Gilmore, 1998-2002
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of Virginia Governor James S. Gilmore, 1998-2002
The Library of Virginia
38938, 38993, 38990, 38995-38997, 39023, 39024, 39044, 39772-39777, 40170, 40171, 40172, 40173, 40174.
102 cu. ft., 104 boxes
Governor James S. Gilmore
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Some records have been sealed and access is denied due to legally required privacy protection.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor
Historical Information
James Stuart Gilmore III was elected Virginia's 68th Governor in November 1997 and served in this capacity from January 1998 to January 2002. Jim Gilmore was born in Richmond, Virginia, on October 6, 1949. He graduated from the University of Virginia in 1971 with a degree in Foreign Policy and then joined the U.S. Army, where he then graduated with honors from the Army Intelligence School. He joined the 650th Military Intelligence Group and was stationed in West Germany. After his tour was completed, he entered law school at the University of Virginia and graduated in 1977. Jim Gilmore was elected in 1987 as Commonwealth's Attorney for Henrico County, was reelected in 1991 and was elected Virginia's Attorney General in 1983. He is married to the former Roxane Gatling of Suffolk.
Records of Governor Gilmore were transferred on January 11, 2002 and November 17, 2002. After the first transfer, it was soon discoverd that only a fraction of the records listed on the approved Records Retention and Disposition Schedule for the Governor's Office had been transferred to the Library of Virginia. After this realization, LVA senior management contacted Gov. Gilmore and his former staff members and began discussions in June 2002 that eventually escalated to legal negotiations over the official gubernatorial papers. A final agreement was reached in November 2002 and the contested 228 boxes of records were finally transferred to the Library of Virginia a few days later.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the executive papers transferred from the office of James Stuart Gilmore III (1998-2002), the sixty-eighth Governor of Virginia. The collection is housed in one hundred (141) boxes and is arranged into twenty-one series. Includes records from the Counselor's Office, Press Office, Executive Mansion, Scheduling Office, and the Constituent Services. Records consist of correspondence, certificates of recognition, event files, invitations, itineraries, photographs, press releases, reports, speeches and other files.
Major issues and initiatives of the Gilmore Administration documented in these records include the car tax, Standards of Learning, several trade missions, and the 9/11 Attack and the response to the threat of terrorism.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Records of the Counsel to the Governor, 1973-2002 (Accession 39024).
Series II. Press Office: Media Advisories, 1998-2002 (Accession 39773).
Series III. Press Office: News Releases and Newsclippings, 1998-2002 (Accession 38995).
Series IIIa. Press Office: News clipping subject and chronological files, 1998-2001 (Accession 40170).
Series IV. Press Office: Speeches, 1998-2002 (Accession 40172).
Series V. Press Office: Photographs, 1998-2001 circa (Accession 38996, 40171).
Series VI. Executive Mansion: Director's Corresondence, 1998-2001 (Accession 39023).
Series VII. Executive Mansion: Event files, 1998-2001 (Accession 39023)
Series VIII. Scheduling Office: Invitations, 1997-2001 (Accession 38990).
Series IX. Constituent Services: Gift Files, 1998-2001 (Accession 38939).
Series X. Constituent Services: Daily Updates and Website Changes, 1999 (Accession 38939).
Series XI. Constituent Services: Mass Mailing Lists, 2000 (Accession 38939).
Series XII. Constituent Services: Patrick Henry Awards, 2001 (Accession 38939).
Series XIII. Constituent Services: Governor's Outreach Network, 1999-2000 (Accession 38939).
Series XIV. Constituent Services: Library of Virginia's Governor's Records Transfer Listings (Accession 38939).
Series XV. Constituent Services: Intern Listings, 2001, (Accession 38939).
Series XVI. Constituent Services: Governor's Fellows Program, 1998-2001(Accession 38939).
Series XVII. Constituent Services: Certificates of Recognitions and Messages, 1998-2001 (Accession 38939).
Series XVIII. Constituent Services: Constituent Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Accession 38938).
Series XIX. Scheduling Office: Event files, 1998-2002 Jan (Accession 40173).
Series XX. Scheduling Office: Reading files, 1997-2002 Jan (Accession 40173, 40174).
Series XXI. Chief of Staff: Correspondence and memoranda, 1998-2001 (Accession 39777).
Series XXII. Executive Office: Executive orders, 1998-2001 (Accession 39775).
Contents List
- Series I. Records of the Counsel to the Governor (Accession 39024), 1973-2002., Extent: 5 cu. ft. (Box 1-5)
  The majority of the records in this series document Walter S. Felton Jr.'s role as Deputy Chief of Policy and Deputy Counselor to the Governor. These records document advice provided to the Governor and his staff to assist in decision making efforts. Records include budget materials, correspondence, feasibility studies, legislative proposals and memoranda. Topics covered include the Property Tax Relief Act of June 1999 ("No Car Tax" proposal), Short Pump Development Project, major league baseball team and stadium proposals, transportation issues, tobacco settlement fund, Virginia's response to the 9/11 terrorist attacks and Governor Gilmores' participation as chair of an advisory panel to assess the country's capabilities to prevent any further terrorist attack.
  These records also include files related to the nominations of members to the Judicial Inquiry Review Commission, preparations for the visit of Ms. Coretta Scott King to commemorate the life and legacy of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr., and recognize the state's agreement to officially acknowledge the national holiday in his honor, and records related to two controversial issues during the Gilmore administration, the Hugh Finn life support case and Ricky Cullipher criminal juvenile justice case. (these files contain some restricted materials sealed due to legal confidentiality laws).
  This series also includes many reports and studies covering a variety of topics of concern to the Commonwealth, among them are the following: Department of Transportation Consultants Report, 1998; Six Year Improvement Plan, Department of Transportation 1998-1999; Internet Policy for the Commonwealth, 1998. These records are part of accession 39024.
  Arrange alphabetically by subject.
  - Archiving Procedures, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Blue Ribbon Commission on Higher Education,1998-2000. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blue Ribbon Commission on Higher Education Final Report,2000. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Budget Process-Balanced Budget Plan,2001. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budget Process-Spending Reduction,2001. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget Process-Restriction on hiring or positions,2001. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget Process-Appropriation Transfer,2001. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Budget Process-Withholding of Appropriations,2001. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budget Process-Moratorium on General Fund Appropriations,2001. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Budget Process-Form 27 Request Budget Adjustments,2001. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budget Process-Direct Aid to Public Education,2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Budget Process-Direct Aid to Public Education,2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Budget Process-Direct Aid to Public Education,2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Budget Process-Direct Aid to Public Education,2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Budget Process-Direct Aid to Public Education,2002. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget Process-Walter S. Felton FOIA Confidential Response Guidelines,2001. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Budget Process-Delegate Whittington W. Clement FOIA Request,2001. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Budget Process-Delegate Alan A. Diamonstein FOIA Request,2001. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget Process-Delegate Franklin P. Hall FOIA Request,2001. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Budget Process-Senator Madison Marye FOIA Request,2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Budget Process-Senator Madison Marye FOIA Request,2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Budget Process-Delegate Kenneth Plum FOIA Request,2001. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Budget Process-Secretary Louis F. Rossiter FOIA Request,2001. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Budget Process-Delegate Marion Van Landingham FOIA Request,2001. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Budget Process-Capital Project Freeze,2001. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Budget Process-Capital Project Freeze,2001. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Buy Virginia,2001. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Car Tax (Personal Property Tax Relief),1998-2001. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of Ascertainment,2000. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Commerce and Trade,2000-2001. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Commission on Transportation Policy,1999-2000. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Comptroller Report to the Governor,1998. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Comptroller Report to the Governor,1999. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Confederate History Month,2000-2001. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Criminal Justice Computer System Assessment,2000-2001. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Criminal Justice Integrated/Information System (Business Case for),2001. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cullipher, Ricky, Clemency Request,1998-1999. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cullipher, Ricky, Clemency Request,1996-1999. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cullipher, Ricky, Clemency Request-Book-The Hyperactive Child Adolescent and Adult ADD through Lifespan,1973. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cullipher, Ricky, Court of Appeals Documents,1999. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cullipher, Ricky, Surveillance Videotape-VHS 60 minutes,undated. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Debt Capacity Advisory Committee,1998. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Department of Motor Vehicles Third Party Testing Program,2001. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Economic Recovery Taskforce,2000-2001. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Education Military Personnel's Children,1995-2001. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Education Higher Decentralization Report,1997-1998. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Elimination of Use Identification and Resident Documents,2001. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Emergency Services (FEMA Commonwealth Agreement),1999-2000. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Finance Secretariat's Plan,1996-2001. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Finn, Hugh Appeal Case Documentation,1999-2000. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Finn, Hugh, Appeals Petition,1999. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Finn, Hugh, Appellee and Appellants Briefs Replies Supreme Court,1999. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Finn, Hugh, Background Case,1999. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Finn, Hugh, Legal Fees Request,1998-1999. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Finn, Hugh, Supreme Court Case,1998-1999. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Freedom of Information Act,2000-2001. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fort Pickett,1999. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Government Performance Project 2000-Virginia Response,2000. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Government Performance Project 2000-Virginia Response,2000. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Government Performance Project 2000-Virginia Response CD,2000. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Government Performance Project Survey,2000. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Government Performance Project Survey Responses,1998. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Governor,2000-2001. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hammond Commission,1998. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Internet Policy,1998. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation Product,2001. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Joint Legislative Audit Commission: Review of the Use of Consultants by VDOT,1998. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Judicial Review Commission-Inquiry and Review Commission Appointees,1999-2001. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Judicial Review Commission-Judicial Questionnaire,1999-2001. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Judicial Review Commission-Public Comments,1997-1999. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Major League Baseball-Economic and Fiscal Impact of a Major League Baseball Franchise and Stadium on the Commonwealth,2000. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Major League Baseball-Economic and Fiscal Impact of a Major League Baseball (Draft)2000. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Major League Baseball Report Financing Options for Purpose of Constructing a Baseball Stadium in Virginia,1997. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Marks, Morton, Bankruptcy Case,1998. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Martin Luther King Jr., Briefing Book,2001. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Martin Luther King Jr., Memorial Commission,2001. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Martin Luther King Jr., Right Choice for Youth Event Fund,2001-2002. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Martin Luther King Jr., Tree Dedication Ceremony,2001. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Medical Assistance Dept., of, Best Management Practices Team,1999. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Mental Health, Retardation and Substance Abuse Comprehensive State Plan 2000-2006,2000. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Mental Health Retardation and Substance Abuse Service System Summary of Philosophical Statements and Recommendations 1990 to present,1998. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Law (NCCUSL)-Revision of the Uniform Limit Partnership Act (1976),2001. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NCCUSL-Amendments to Uniform Interstate Family Support Act,2001. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - NCCUSL-Amendments to Uniform Consumer Leases Act,2001. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - NCCUSL-Revision of Uniform Commercial Code,2001. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - NCCUSL-Uniform Mediation Act,2001. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - National Governor's Association,2001. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - National Governor's Association-Policy Positions,2000-2001. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - National Governor's Association-Policy Positions,2001. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - National Governor's Conference Conservation and Reinvestment Act,2001. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Natural Resources-Central Intelligence Agency Request of Department of Environmental Quality,2001. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Natural Resources-Historic Rehabilitation Tax Credit,2001. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Natural Resources-Natural Gas Severance Tax,2001. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Natural Resources-King William Reservoir Project,2001. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Natural Resources-Report Virginia Wetlands Restoration Coordinating Committee,2001. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Natural Resources-Water Supply in Virginia Coal Field Counties Status Technical Options, Assessing Rate Impacts,1997. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pardons and Red Onion State Prisons,2000-2001. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Pfiesteria Piscicida-Virginia Water Study,1997-1998. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Planning and Performance Virginia's Handbook,1998. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Planning and Performance Virginia's Handbook,1998. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Privitization/Competition Manual,1998. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Protecting Virginia's Places of Worship,1993-1996. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Rail and Public Transit Study,2001. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Recodification of Title 2.1 and Portions of Title 9 Code of Virginia,2000. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Records Retention,2000-2001. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Report: Governor's Taskforce on Procurement Assessment Recommendations to Improve Governments Procurement System,2000. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Speaking Engagement-Walter S., Fenton Jr.,2001. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Special Sessions Legislation,1998. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Standards of Learning for Virginia Public Schools,undated. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Strategies for Excellence: State Council for Higher Education Annual Report,1999. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Terrorism and Cyberterrorism Task Force,2000-2001. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Tobacco-Annual Report Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission,2000-2001. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Tobacco Economic Development,1999-2001. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Tobacco Farmer Relief Initiative and Economic Revitalization Plan for South Virginia,1999. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Tobacco Foundation,1999-2002. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission,1999-2001. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Commission,2001. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Tobacco Legislation (Federal),1998. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Tobacco Loss Assistance Program,2000. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Tobacco National Governor's Association Spending Initiatives,2001. (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Tobacco National Tobacco Grower Settlement Trust,1999-2001. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Tobacco Trust Certification Board,2000-2002. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Tobacco Workers Unity Summit Protecting Our Children, Protecting Our Jobs,1998 June 11. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Transportation-Ad-Hoc Study Committee for Size and Weight Limits, Report of Dept. of Motor Vehicles, Transportation, State Police and Representatives of the Motor Carrier Industry,2001. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Transportation-Innovations in Transportation Finance,1999 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Transportation Issues,2000. (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Transportation-Northern Virginia 2020 Transportation Plan,1991. (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Transportation-Reshaping the Virginia Department of Transportation, An Assessment of Accomplishments for 2000,2000. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Transportation-Six Year Improvement Program,1998-1999. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Transportation-Six Year Improvement Program Tentative,1999-2000. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Twenty Eighth Infantry Regiment Flag Issue,2001. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - United-U.S. Airways,2000. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - VetNet America,2000. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Virginia's Future,The Promise for,1998. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Geographic Information Network,undated. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume I.- Secretary of Administration,1994-1997. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume I.- Compensation Board to Housing and Community Development,1994-1997. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume I.- Department of Mines, Minerals and Energy to Virginia Racing Commission,1994-1996. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume II.- Department of Education,1994-1996. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume III.- Library of Virginia to Department of Rehabilitative Services,1994-1997. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume III.- Department of Social Services to Virginia's Peoples' Board of Disabilities,1994-1997. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume III.- Department of Visually Handicapped to Department of Health,1994-1997. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume III.- Secretary of Natural Resources to Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance,1994-1995. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume III.- Department of Conservation and Recreation to Virginia's Marine Source Commission,1994-1995. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume IV.- Secretary of Public Safety, Secretary of Transportation to Virginia Department of Emergency Services,1994-1995. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Virginia's Local Governments Assessment of Mandates Volume IV.- Virginia State Police to State Executive Council,1994-1997. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Virginia National Guard,2000. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Waste Management,1998-2000. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Woodrow Wilson Bridge,2001. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Y2K,1999. (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Series II. Press Office: Media Advisories (Accession 39773), 1998-2002., Extent: .35 cu. ft. (Box 5A)
  This series consists media advisories that include news announcements sent from the Press Office to reporters, news editors and other members of the media alerting them of the Governor's public schedule of appearances, major announcements, attendance at certain events, bill signing, speeches given and radio interviews. The records also include First Lady Roxanne Gilmore's public announcements and appearances. These records are also available electronically on compact disk. (Accession 39773).
  Arranged chronologically by date.
  - Media Advisories, 1998 June. (Box 5A, Folder 1)
  - Media Advisories, 1998 July. (Box 5A, Folder 2)
  - Media Advisories, 1998 August. (Box 5A, Folder 3)
  - Media Advisories, 1998 September. (Box 5A, Folder 4)
  - Media Advisories, 1998 October. (Box 5A, Folder 5)
  - Media Advisories, 1998 November. (Box 5A, Folder 6)
  - Media Advisories, 1998 December. (Box 5A, Folder 7)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 January. (Box 5A, Folder 8)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 February. (Box 5A, Folder 9)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 March. (Box 5A, Folder 10)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 April. (Box 5A, Folder 11)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 May. (Box 5A, Folder 12)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 June. (Box 5A, Folder 13)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 July. (Box 5A, Folder 14)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 August. (Box 5A, Folder 15)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 September. (Box 5A, Folder 16)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 October. (Box 5A, Folder 17)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 November. (Box 5A, Folder 18)
  - Media Advisories, 1999 December. (Box 5A, Folder 19)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 January. (Box 5A, Folder 20)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 February. (Box 5A, Folder 21)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 March. (Box 5A, Folder 22)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 April. (Box 5A, Folder 23)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 May. (Box 5A, Folder 24)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 June. (Box 5A, Folder 25)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 July. (Box 5A, Folder 26)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 September. (Box 5A, Folder 27)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 October. (Box 5A, Folder 28)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 November. (Box 5A, Folder 29)
  - Media Advisories, 2000 December. (Box 5A, Folder 30)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 January. (Box 5A, Folder 31)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 February. (Box 5A, Folder 32)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 March. (Box 5A, Folder 33)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 April. (Box 5A, Folder 34)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 May. (Box 5A, Folder 35)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 June. (Box 5A, Folder 36)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 July. (Box 5A, Folder 37)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 August. (Box 5A, Folder 38)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 September. (Box 5A, Folder 39)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 October. (Box 5A, Folder 40)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 November. (Box 5A, Folder 41)
  - Media Advisories, 2001 December. (Box 5A, Folder 42)
  - Media Advisories, 2002 January. (Box 5A, Folder 43)
  - Media Advisories and News Releases CD, 1998-2002. (Box 5A, Folder 44)
- Series III. Press Office: News Releases and Newsclippings (Accession 38995 and 39772), 1998-2002., Extent: 3 cu. ft. (Box 6-8)
  This series consists of daily news releases (accession 38995) provided to the press by the Governor's Office and daily clippings of news (accession 39772) provided to the Governor and his staff for review. The press releases include information on such topics as appointments to boards, proclamations, recognition of important events, announcements related to new businesses in Virginia, and information on clemency and or executions. The releases have an alphabetical/chronological index before each year, providing both subject access and date access for the news releases. The news clippings consist of pertinent clippings on compact disk, selected each day by press offic staff for review by the Governor and his staff.
  - News Releases Index, 1998. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - News Releases, 1998 Jan 5. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - News Releases, 1998 Jan 10. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - News Releases, 1998 January 16. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - News Releases, 1998 January 21. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - News Releases, 1998 January 22. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - News Releases, 1998 January 23. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - News Releases, 1998 January 26. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - News Releases, 1998 January 28. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - News Releases, 1998 January 29. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - News Releases, 1998 February 2. (Box 6, Folder 11)